<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?Inspire CreateDate="2019-02-20T20:22:31" ModifiedDate="2022-04-08T13:52:13"?><!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd"><concept xml:lang="en-us" id="GUID-9F952B91-D1B4-47D2-B687-CAAED6443CA4"><title id="GUID-F58C456B-91AC-4C0C-BB23-3BF7C6930D4B">Configuration of web service listen
		connections</title><shortdesc>For connectors that use the shared web server to manage incoming traffic, connection
		settings are controlled at the Atom level on the <uicontrol>Shared Web Server</uicontrol>
		panel within Atom Management. </shortdesc><prolog><resourceid id="GUID-9F952B91-D1B4-47D2-B687-CAAED6443CA4" /></prolog><conbody><p>In standard <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_INTEGRATION"></keyword> connectors, a connection component is paired with an operation component to build a
			direct link to a desired application or data source. This is not the case for connectors
			that use the shared web server to manage incoming traffic. For API publishing,
			connection settings are controlled at the Atom level, so the same web server can be used
			for all processes that are deployed to the Atom. </p><p>The Shared Web Server panel (<menucascade>
				<uicontrol>Manage</uicontrol>
				<uicontrol> Atom Management</uicontrol>
				<uicontrol> Settings and Configuration</uicontrol>
				<uicontrol> Shared Web Server</uicontrol>
			</menucascade>) is used to specify URL requirements and to control network and security
			settings at the account and account user level. The maximum number of configurable API
			users, including the account itself, is specified by the container property
				<codeph>com.boomi.container.sharedServer.http.maxSoaUsers</codeph>. The default
			number of API users is 200, which is the maximum number allowed by the <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword>
			<keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/PLATFORM"></keyword>. You may want to set this to a smaller number for your Atom. For information about
			configuring access to API processes at the individual user level, see the topic about
			securing APIs. </p><p><draft-comment author="Jon_Brams">BOOMI-38209 update</draft-comment>The AS2 Shared Server and
			Web Services Server connectors use the shared web server to manage incoming traffic.
			Their connection components are not predefined. You must create a process to use the
			shared web server settings along with the associated operation. The process(es)
			containing the connectors must be deployed to launch web server listening and to route
			the proper documents to a process. If you are using API Management, you must likewise
			deploy the API Service component in which an API endpoint(s) are defined that link to
			the process(es). See the connector topics linked below for information about configuring
			the operations for each connector. See the related topic about Designing APIs for
			information about generating and configuring API endpoints. </p><note id="GUID-51D68E38-260C-4FFC-9E35-C31B999D61C2">Review the Web Services Server
			Operation Configuration topic to learn how to construct advanced API scenarios and
			implement response paging. </note><section id="GUID-23A339D3-57A1-401B-9F20-9CC8BA8A5704">
			<title id="GUID-069AD368-EF2D-40DD-8893-16520990A02E">Base URL</title>
			<p>The base URL for an Atom’s deployed APIs is shown in the Atom’s Shared Web Server
				panel. By default this URL is constructed based on the Atom’s host name or external
				host name and the shared web server’s port/SSL port settings. </p>
			<ul id="GUID-A44F857B-DC35-4933-B296-75784EFBD28B"><li id="li_fd582fdf-eccd-43d2-984f-de0c37f37227">
					<draft-comment author="Jon_Brams">BOOMI-36910 converted to external link
						(peer-scoped would not work in output)</draft-comment>
					<p>For a <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword> Atom Cloud or Test Atom Cloud, use the domain name shown in <xref href="https://help.boomi.com/csh?context=GUID-56963A56-5B61-4323-8510-E32CF810880C&amp;pubname=atomsphere" format="html" scope="external">Hostnames and IP addresses for the
								<keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword> Atom Clouds</xref>. </p>
				</li></ul>
		</section><section id="GUID-FFBC9222-52E6-493A-9DFA-6CBD38642EB1">
			<title id="GUID-6AE4EC14-2098-4FEE-AD4F-2DF5FF0B5893">Listen connections on local
				Atoms</title>
			<p>If you want to publish APIs that integrate with on-premise applications or data
				sources behind your firewall, you need to deploy the integration process to a local
				Atom that has access to those resources. </p>
			<p>If you are using a local Atom within a secure network, you should configure your
				firewall/router to route incoming messages to this Atom. The proper ports should be
				opened for the Atom web server to receive messages. </p>
			<p>The web server settings can be configured to forward requests to a standard HTTP or
				HTTPS address. </p>
			<table id="TABLE_6C94F05638064FC9B92388079AC5E132"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="*" /><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="*" /><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="*" /><tbody><row><entry colname="col1"><uicontrol>Definition URL
									(recommended):</uicontrol>
							</entry><entry colname="col2"><codeph>http(s)://&lt;External/Internal
									Host&gt;:&lt;Port&gt;/ws/soap?wsdl</codeph>
							</entry><entry colname="col3">Used to output multi-file WSDLs. </entry></row><row><entry colname="col1"><uicontrol>Definition URL:</uicontrol>
							</entry><entry colname="col2"><codeph>http(s)://&lt;External/Internal
									Host&gt;:&lt;Port&gt;/ws/soap?wsdl=single</codeph>
							</entry><entry colname="col3">Used to create a WSDL merged into one file, with
								inline schemas and no includes. </entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
		</section><section id="GUID-5D1F25B7-3AB3-4E45-BE7E-14EEC994EFE7">
			<title id="GUID-1898F4AB-BB58-41F8-ABD1-3EF77A398BF9">Listen connections on the Boomi Atom Clouds</title>
			<p>Each <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword> Atom Cloud’s Atom instance manages the authentication token settings for your
				account ID and the Atom Cloud's domain name. For all Atom Clouds, the token
				(password) is accessible from the Atom Management page. </p>
			<p>The web server settings for an Atom Cloud's domain name are managed in the <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword> Atom Cloud on the Atom Management page. By default, the connection requires an
				HTTPS address and BASIC authentication to connect. If you are accessing the WSDL via
				a browser or SOAP client, you will be prompted for a user name and password. </p>
			<dl><dlentry id="GUID-1DA2BB18-00C6-4E25-B268-639290934F83"><dt><uicontrol>Sample Definition URL</uicontrol>
					</dt><dd>
						<codeblock xml:space="preserve" outputclass="code-java">https://c01-usa-east-integrate.boomi.com/ws/soap?wsdl</codeblock>
					</dd></dlentry></dl>
		</section><section id="GUID-BE674A5D-4663-443D-879F-4F4141ECDCD6">
			<title id="GUID-791D3F33-DFBC-403C-A443-151ED323EF73">Listen connections on the Boomi Test Atom Clouds</title>
			<p>The above information regarding <keyword conref="lib-Boomi_Keywords_0346af2b-13d7-491e-bec9-18c5d89225bf.xml#GUID-0207C7F1-40FD-4537-BE59-1D6DA46B9A1D/BOOMI_DELL"></keyword> Atom Cloud connections otherwise applies to the Test Atom Clouds. The only aspect
				of Test Atom Cloud connections that differs is the presence of the subdomain “test”
				in the base URL. </p>
		</section><section id="GUID-5AEA025C-B618-4A78-BA3B-FC6BB09DB47A">
			<title id="GUID-D792DF04-8054-4D3E-A7E7-38C74B46D3F3">Protected input headers</title>
			<p>Protected input headers can be configured for an Atom’s shared web server in the
				Shared Web Server panel. When a header is protected, its value in a REST/SOAP/simple
				HTTP request cannot be passed to the web service listener process execution as a
				dynamic document property. </p>
			<p>The following HTTP headers are designated as protected in the shared web server’s
				default configuration: </p>
			<table id="GUID-8F5B457C-C678-49A7-BB12-A54B3521C148" conref="lib-AtomSphere_API_9a0b3cc6-0758-45f9-b2cc-04932561d53c.xml#GUID-3B92F5CD-0A69-4191-BF29-297025332DDB/GUID-C7CF72C9-C6CA-43DF-A310-3E84E3D3BA0D"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" /><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" /><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" /><tbody><row><entry colname="col1"> </entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
		</section></conbody></concept>